Guide to the Incunabula Collection at Stanford University, 1467-1500
Department of Special Collections
- Melber, Johannes, 15th cent. Vocabularius predicantium.[Strasbourg: Georg Husner, 1497?], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1497 .M45; [344] p.; 21 cm.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Imperfect: t.-p. and leaves a8 and e8 wanting. Binding: brown morocco; gilt decorated spine. Binder's title: Vocabularius. Provenance: The Hildebrand Library (ink- stamp); ms. emendations, underscoring and marginalia.
- Razi, Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Zakariya, 865?-925? Contenta in hoc volumine ...[Venice]: Mandato [et] expensis ... Octauiani Scoti ... per Bonetum Locatellum ..., 1497, die septimo me[n]sis Octobris., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1497 .R37 f; 159, [1] leaves (the last leaf blank); 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 448 (IB.22966). Goff (rev.), R-176. Hain-Copinger, 13893. ISTC (RLIN), ir00176000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: quarter leather; grey boards; leather clasps. Provenance: ms. marginalia. With: Ibn Zuhr, Abd al-Malik. Abumeron Auenzohar. Impressi Venetijs: P[er] Ioannem de Forliuio [et] Gregoriu[m] fratres, anno Salutis 1490 [i.e. 1491] die q[ua]rta me[n]sis Ianuarij.
- Ibn Zuhr, Abd al-Malik ibn Abi al-Ala(r), d. 1162. Abumeron Auenzohar. Colliget Auerroys. Cited as: Liber Teisir Impressi Venetijs: P[er] Ioannem de Forliuio [et] Gregoriu[m] fratres, anno Salutis 1490 [i.e. 1491] die q[ua]rta me[n]sis Ianuarij., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1497 .R37 f; [4], 40, [1], 2-63, [1] leaves; 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 341 (IB.20989). GW 3103. Goff (rev.), A-1408. Hain 2186. ISTC (RLIN), ia01408000. Pellechet 1652.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Imperfect: all after leaf 40 (1st group) [i.e. Colliget Averros] lacking. Provenance: ms. marginalia and underscoring. With: Razi, Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Zakariya. Contenta in hoc volumine ... [Venice]: Mandato [et] expensis ... Octauiani Scoti ... per Bonetum Locatellum ..., 1497, die septimo me[n]sis Octobris.
- Schedel, Hartmann, 1440-1514. Liber cronicarum: cum figuris et ymaginibus ab inicio mu[n]di vsq[ue] nu[n]c temporis.[Augsburg]: Impressum ac finitu[m] in vigilia Purificatio[n]is Marie in imp[er]iali vrbe Augusta a Iohanne Schensperger, anno ab Incarnatio[n]e Domini 1497 [1 Feb.], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1497 .S3 f; [26], cccxxxviii [i.e. 339], [1] leaves, [2] folded leaves: ill., maps; 31 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., II, p. 370 (IB.6361). Goff (rev.), S-308. Hain-Copinger-Reichling 14509. ISTC (RLIN), is00308000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Collation as in BM 15th cent., II, p. 370 (IB.6361), with addition of map as described in Hain-Copinger- Reichling, 14509. Rubrication: initial strokes in red. Imperfect: blanks [****]8 and 2O6 and t.p. of register lacking; title of register salvaged and mounted on blank replacement leaf. Binding errors: leaf xlix bound before leaf xlviii; leaf cclxi bound before leaf cclx. Binding: calf; gilt decoration; panelled spine with gilt decoration and 2 title labels; marbled endpapers and edges. Binder's title: Liber cronicarum ab initio mundi. Provenance: Collegij Societatis Jesu Spirae (inscription); extensive ms. marginalia and underscoring.
- Tacitus, Cornelius. Cornelij Taciti Historiae Augustae.[Venice]: Venetijs fideliter impresi ac diligenter emendati p[er] Philippu[m] Pinci sumptibus nobilis viri D[omi]ni Benedicti Fontana, anno D[omi]ni Mccccxcvij die xxij Marcij [22 March 1497], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1497 .T33 f; [228] p. (last p. blank); 30 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent. V, p. 497 (IB.23674). Goff (rev.), T-8. Hain-Copinger 15222. ISTC (RLIN), it00008000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding error: duplicate i3 bound in. Binding: half marbled leather, marbled boards and endpapers. Binder's title: Liber historiae Augustae Tacitus--1497. Extensive ms. marginalia, fists, and underscoring; extensive ms. notations on final page; some loss of ms. marginalia throughout due to trimming. The f missigned on d1 d2 crossed out in ink.
- Aristophanes. Aristophanous Komodiai ennea = Aristophanis Comoediae novem ... Venetiis: Apud Aldum, 1498 Idibus Quintilis [15 Jul. 1498], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .A73 F; [696] (last 2 blank) p.; 33 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 559 (IB.24470). GW 2333. Goff (rev.), A-958. Hain-Copinger, 1656. ISTC (RLIN), ia00958000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Imperfect: last (blank) leaf lacking. Binding: calf with panelled spine; gilt decorated; marbled end-papers. Binder's title: Comoediae Graece. Provenance: Ciccolini (ink- stamp).
- Uniform Title: Bible. Latin. Vulgate. 1498. Title: Biblia cum tabula nuper impressa [et] cum summariis nouiter editis. Impressum Venetijs: P[er] Symonem dictu[m] Beuilaqua, 1498, die octauo Maij [8 May 1498]., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .B5; [1056] p.: ill. (woodcuts); 22 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 522 (IA.23978). GW 4280. Goff B-603. Hain-Copinger 3124. ISTC (RLIN), IB00603000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: untouched. Ms. fists; foliated in ms. Binding: half brown leather, paper boards, with spine title: Biblia Latina in ink. Imperfect: wanting all before b1; wanting c2, d7, f1, g6, i2, k3, l3, l5, n1, o3, p6, r1, s1-s8, t1, t4, v2, v7, x8, y4, z1, z6, [et]8, B1, C1, C4, C6, D3, F3, H5, L2, L4, L6, O1, P1, P4, P6, P8-Q2, Q4-Q6, Q8-R1, R4, R6, U3, Xy, Y8, 2a4, 2b6, 2c2, 2c7, 2d3-2d4, 2d6-2d7, 2e1-2e6, 2f2, and all after 2f8. Title and imprint supplied from BM 15th cent., V, p. 522 (IA.23978).
- Dares, Phrygius. Historia Troiana secundu[m] Daretem Phrijgium.[Leipzig: Martin Landsberg, not before 12 July 1498], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .D37; [56] p.; 21 cm.
  References: Indexed by: BM 15th cent., III, p. 641 (IA.11901).; Indexed by: GW 7991.; Indexed by: Goff (rev.), D-43.; Indexed by: Hain-Copinger 5962.; Indexed by: ISTC (RLIN), id00043000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Has the variant on leaf 3r line 13 mentioned in GW 7991 Anm. Binding: black boards; title label on upper cover. Provenance: Rud. Hildebrand (signature); The Hildebrand Library (ink-stamp); extensive ms. marginalia and underscoring.
- Gaguin, Robert, 1433-1501. In hoc volumine hec continentur Roberti Gaguini iuris canonici interpretis epistole: eiusdem quedam orationes: eiusdem De conceptione virginis defensio: eiusdem de eade[m] conceptione ad fratres sui ordinis or[ati]o: eiusdem de arte metrificandi precepta: eiusdem epigrammata: eiusdem de Christi morte atq[ue] resurrectione: item de miserijs humane vite et contra poesis detractores breues tractatuli metro scripti. Added title page title: Tractatus Roberti Gagu[in]i De puritate conceptionis[Paris]: Durandi Gerleri biblyopole Parisiaci i[m]pensa impressa sunt ... p[er] mag[ist]r[u]m Andrea[m] Bocard, anno D[omi]ni 1498 Noue[m]b[ris] secunda et vigesima [22 Nov. 1498], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .G34; [204] p.; 20 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., VIII, p. 156 (IA.40229). GW 10438. Goff (rev.), G-20. Hain-Copinger 7425. ISTC (RLIN), ig00020000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Imperfect: consists of 2nd part only. Binding: calf; gilt decorated panelled spine; marbled end-papers. Provenance: Franklin H. Chase (bookplate); ms. marginalia.
- Nepos, Cornelius. Aemilii Probi historici Excellentium imperatorum vitae. Impressum Venetiis: Per Bernardinum Venetum, [ca. 1498-1500], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .N47; [100] p.; 21 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 550 (IA.24359). Goff (rev.), C-918. Hain 5732. ISTC, ic00918000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: ms. fragment. Provenance: [V. Conv. Medhinga?] (inscription); Ioannes Baijor (inscription); Conventus Augustani FF. Praedicat. (inscription); ms. marginalia and underscoring.
- Pico della Mirandola, Giovanni, 1463-1494. Ioannis Pici Mirandulae Omnia opera ... Added title page title: Disputationes Ioannis Pici Mirandulae litterarum principis aduersus astrologia[m] diuinatrice[m] quibus penitus subneruata corruit Short title: Omnia opera Bononiae: Impressit Benedictus Hectoris Bononiensis, anno Salutis 1495 die uero XVI Iulii [i.e. Impressit Venetiis: Per Bernardinu[m] Venetu[m], anno Salutis 1498 die uero XIIII Augusti] [14 Aug. 1498], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .P39 F; [524] p.; 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 548 (IB.24328). Goff (rev), P-634. Hain-Copinger, 12993. Hain 12994. ISTC (RLIN), ip00634000. Polain 3144a.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Variant: contains 1st state of 2nd colophon as described in Polain, 3144a. Binding: full vellum; marbled end- papers. Binder's title: Opera. Provenance: Henry Reeve (armorial bookplate).
- Poliziano, Angelo, 1454-1494. Omnia opera Angeli Politiani: et alia quaedam lectu digna, quorum nomina in sequenti indice uidere licet. Venetiis: In aedibus Aldi Romani, mense Iulio 1498., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .P67 F; [904] p. (last p. blank); 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 559 (IB.24475). Goff (rev.), P-886. Hain-Copinger, 13218. ISTC (RLIN), ip00886000. Polain 3233.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: full vellum. Provenance: Viscount Mersey (booklabel).
- Solinus, C. Julius, 3rd cent.? Solinus De memoralibus mundi. Venetiis: [Joannes Rubeus Vercellensis], anno Domini 1498, die x. Marci., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .S6; [92] (last blank) p.; 21 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 420 (IA.23190). Goff (rev.), S-622. Hain-Copinger 14885. ISTC (RLIN), is00622000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binder: Emile Rouselle (stamp). Binding: red morocco with panelled spine and turn-ins, all gilt decorated; marbled endpapers. Binder's title: Solinus Memoralibus mundi.
- Tauler, Johannes, ca. 1300-1361. Sermon des gross gelarten in gnade[n] erlauchte[n] Doctoris Johannis Thauleri Predigerr Ordens: weisende auff den neheste[n] waren wegk: yn Geiste czu wa[n]dern durch vberschwebe[n]den syn. vnuoracht vo[n] Geistes ynnige[n] vorwa[n]delt i[n] deutsch ma[n]che[n] Me[n]sche[n] zu selikeit. Gedruckt in der furstlichen Stat Leyptzk: Durch Cunradum Kachelouen ..., am Tag Gerdrudis ym acht und neuntzigiste[n] Iar [17 Mar. 1498], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1498 .T38; [8], cclxxxi [i.e. cclxxxii] leaves; 21 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., III, p. 628 (IA.12345). Goff (rev.), T-48. Hain-Copinger 15346 ISTC (RLIN), it00048000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: initial capital supplied in red; underscoring. Imperfect: leaves i-vi damaged, with missing text supplied in ms. T.p. mounted. Binding: gray boards, with title label on spine reading: Thauler. Provenance: Ex libris Jean [de Aran?] (inscription).
- Baptista, Mantuanus, 1448-1516. Uniform title: De patientia Title: Baptiste Mantuani Carmelite De patientia aurei libri tres. Short title: De patientia aurei libri tres Impr[a]essum Basile[a]e: Opera Ioha[n]nis Bergman de Olpe, xvi kl[endas] Septe[m]bres anno salutis Mcccclxxxxix ... [17 Aug. 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .B3; [236] p.; 22 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., III, p. 797 (IA.37959). GW 3307. Goff(rev.), B-79. Hain-Copinger 2407. ISTC (RLIN), ib00079000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: full vellum; in container. Ms. marginalia (with some loss due to trimming); underscoring.
- Baptista, Mantuanus, 1448-1516. In Robertum Seuerinatem panaegyricum carmen. Venetiis: Impressum est per Iacobum de Leucho, anno natiuitatis Dominice M.cccc.xcix die vi. Augusti [6 August 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .B315; [100] p.; 19 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 565 (IA.24532). Goff (rev.), B-87. GW 3260. Hain 2396. ISTC (RLIN), ib00087000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: boards covered with early printed leaf with German text, rubricated; title label on spine. Binder's title: B. Mantuanus Sec. Parthenice. Provenance: ms. marginalia on C2, trimmed.
- Baptista, Mantuanus, 1448-1516. Parthenice. Impressum Venetiis: Per Iacobum de Leucho, anno gratiae M.xcix die xvi Iulii [16 July 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .B32; [140] p.; 20 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 565 (IA.24534). Goff (rev.), B-63. GW 3287. Hain-Copinger 2368. ISTC (RLIN), ib00063000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: Binding: boards covered with early printed leaf with German text, rubricated. Binder's title: B. Mantuanus Parthenice 1499. Provenance: extensive ms. marginalia, trimmed; extensive ms. interlinear annotations.
- Biel, Gabriel, d. 1495. Epithoma Expositionis canonis Misse Magistri Gabrielis Biel sacre theologie licentiati. In Thuwing[e]n impressum: [Johann Otmar, for Friedrich Meynberger, between 20 Feb. and 29 Nov. 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .B55; [156] p.; 19 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., III, 702 (IA.14821) GW 4334. Goff (rev.), B-654. Hain-Copinger 3181. ISTC (RLIN), ib00654000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: several capitals in red. Initials and paragraph marks in red. Binding: red vellum; in case. Slight loss of text at head due to trimming. Ms. marginalia at head of most pages, with some loss due to trimming. Language: Latin Year: 1499 Item CSUGAKW9812-B (Books) AKW9812 (NOTIS)
- Cicero, Marcus Tullius. Orationes M. Tullii Ciceronis / per Philippu[m] Beroaldu[m] recognitae ac dilige[n]ter correctae; addita in Calce Oratione aduersus Valerium quae hactenus incognita fuit.[Bologna]: Impressit Benedictus Hectoris Bononiensis ..., anno a natali [Chr][ist]i M.CCCC.LXXXXIX idibus Aprilis [13 April 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .C5 F; [542] p. (last p. blank); 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., VI, p. 845 (IB.29095). GW 6771. Goff (rev.), C-549. Hain-Copinger 5129. ISTC (RLIN), ic00549000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: speckled brown calf, marbled boards. Spine title: Ciceronis orationes. Provenance: Albert M. Bender (donor's bookplate); Kno[rren?] (inscription); faint ms. marginalia and annotations, with slight loss due to trimming; scant underscoring.
- Colonna, Francesco, d. 1527. Hypnerotomachia Poliphili ubi humana omnia non nisi somnium esse doce: atque obiter plurima scitu sane quam digna commemorat ... Venetiis: In aedibus Aldi Manutii, accuratissime, mense Decembri M.ID. [Dec. 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .C65 F; [468] p.: ill.; 31 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., v. 5, p. 461 (IB.24500). GW 7223. Goff, C-767. Hain-Copinger, 5501. ISTC (RLIN), ic00767000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: red borders. Binding: limp vellum. Binder's title: Hypneroto-machia P[ro?]liphili. In red morocco case, with spine title: Hypnerotomachia Poliphili. Provenance: Templeton Crocker (booklabel), armorial bookplate with motto "A home a home a home." Line 5 on a1 ends "SANEQV," with an E (?) after the V being erased. Minor ms. additions, some on the illustrations.
- Dragisic, Juraj, ca. 1448-1520. Georgei Benigni Ordinis Minorum sacraru[m] litterarum professoris ad illustrem atq[ue] religiosum Epidaurinum seu Rhacusinum Senatum in librum De natura c[o]elestium spirituum quos angelos uocamus p[ro] hoemium incipit foeliciter. Impressum cum maxima diligentia Florenti[a]e: [Bartolommeo di Libri], XIII Kale[n]das Augusti [20 July] 1499., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .D73; [260] p. (last p. blank); 28 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent, VI, p. 654 (IB.27385). Goff (rev.), B-324. GW 3843. Hain-Copinger, 2783*. ISTC (RLIN), ib00324000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: paragraph marks in red or blue. Binding: half vellum, brown patterned boards. Binder's title: Georgei Benigni De natura angelorum MCCCCXCIX.
- Uniform title: Etymologikon mega kata alphabeton pany ophelimon. Title: Etymologicum magnum Graecum.[Venice: Zacharias Kallierges for Nicolaus Blastus and Anna Notaras, 8 July 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .E87 f; [448] p.; 42 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 580 (IC.24734). Goff (rev.), E-112. GW 9426. Hain-Copinger 6691.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: limp vellum. Binder's title: Etymologi[a] Grec[a]. In box with title: Etymologicum magnum Graecum. Foliation added in pencil. Provenance: Alberici XII Atestii Barbiani et Belgiojosii Principis (armorial bookplate).
- France. La nouuelle ordonnance faicte par le roy n[ost]re sire publiee a Paris le xiii iour de iuing lan mil quatrecens quatre vingtz et dizeneuf: auecques le cry des monnoyes publie en la court de parlement a Paris le lundi xxvii iour de moy lan dessusdit.[Paris]: Jean Trepperel, [1499?], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .F73; [8] p.; 19 cm.
  Stanford Copy
  Stanford copy 1 (RBC): With: France. Les ordonnances royaulx nouuellement publiees a Paris. [Paris?: Jean Trepperel?, 1499?].
- France. Les ordonnances royaulx nouuellement publiees a Paris / faictes par le roy nostre sire le xiii iour du moys d'iuing mil iiii cens quatre vingtz et dixneuf.[Paris?: Jean Trepperel?, 1499?], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .F73; [52] p.; 19 cm.
  Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binder: Honnelaitre (stamp). Binding: half blind-tooled calf, blue boards. Binder's title: Ordonnances royaulx. With: France. La nouuelle ordonnance faicte par le roy n[ost]resire publiee a Paris le xiii iour de iuing lan mil quatrcens quatre vingtz et dizeneuf. [Paris]: Jean Trepperel, [1499?].
- Perotti, Niccol, 1430-1480. Cornucopiae, siue, Linguae Latinae commentarii: ubi quamplurima loca quae in aliis ante impressis incorrecta leguntur emendata sunt: multa praeterea quae in iis etiam quos ex archetypo excriptos habuimus, mendosa erant, emaculauimus ...: index copiosissimus nouo ordine ...: eiusdem Sypontini libellus quo Plinii epistola ad Titum Vespasianu[m] corrigitur cum Graeco ...: Cornelii Vitellii in eum ipsum libellum Sypontini annotationes ... Venetiis: In aedibus Aldi, mense Iulio 1499., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .P36 F; 30 leaves, 642, [2] (blank) p.; 31 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 561 (IB.24495). Goff (rev), P-296. Hain 12706. ISTC (RLIN), ip00296000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: paragraph marks and some initials in red. Binding: brown morocco; panelled spine; both gilt decorated. Binder: Clarke Bedford (stamp). Binder's title: Cornucopiae.
- Poliziano, Angelo, 1454-1494. Uniform Title: Works. 1499 Title: Opera Angeli Politiani: alia quaedam lectu digna, quorum nomina insequenti indice uidere licet. Impressum Florentiae: Op[er]a impensa Leonardi de Arigis de Gesoriaco [i.e. Brescia: Bernardinus de Misintis], die decimo Augusti 1499 [10 Aug. 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .P67 f; [424] p. (last 2 p. blank); 31 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., VII, p. 992 (IB.31268). Goff (rev.), P-887. Hain-Copinger, 13219. ISTC (RLIN ), ip00887000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Imperfect: last leaf (blank) wanting. Binding: half vellum; brown boards. Provenance: ms. marginalia.
- Poliziano, Angelo, 1454-1494. Illustrium viroru[m] epistole ...[Lyon]: In officina Nicolai Vvolf Lutrien[sis], anno a natali Christiano 1499 ad Idus Februarias [13 Feb. 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .P69; [168] (last p. blank) p.; 27 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., VIII, p. 330 (IB.42192). GW 9368. Goff (rev.), E-98. Hain-Copinger 6662. ISTC (RLIN), ip00888200.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: calf; panelled spine with title label. Provenance: Museum Britannicum (ink-stamp); Bibl. Theol. Aberdonensi (ink-stamp).
- Prudentius, b. 348. Uniform: Aurelij Prudentij Clementis nobilissimi ac facundissimi poete Liber historiarum. Title: Aurelii Prudentii Clementis nobilissimi ac facundissimi poete Liber historiarum Short title: Liber historiarum Liptzik: Per Jacobu[m] Tha[n]ner fideliter impressus [et] per magistru[m] Johannem Cubitensem diligenter eme[n]datus, anno Domini 1499 sexto nonas Maias [2 May 1499], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .P78; [16] p. (last p. blank); 21 cm.
  References: Goff (rev.), P-1030. Hain 13434. ISTC (RLIN), ip01030000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Rubrication: scant underscoring in red. Binding: full brown leather, marbled endpapers. Spine title: Prudentius. Provenance: R. Hildebrand (signature); The Hildebrand Library (ink-stamp), with ink-stamp of a three-petaled red flower within shield; Christiani Fridrici Eberhard, Lips. J.V.D. (bookplate).
- Valla, Lorenzo, 406-1457. Hoc in uolumine hec continentur: Laurentii Uallensis Elegantie de lingua Latina; Laurentii Uallensis De pronomine sui ad Joannem Tortelium. Laurentii Uallensis lima quedam / per Antoniu[m] Mancinellu[m]. Impressum Venetiis: Per Io. Baptistam Sessa, anno Domini M.CCCCXCIX. die VIII. Februarii [8 Feb. 1499/1500], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1499 .V36 F; [172] p. (last 2 blank); 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 481 (IB.24559). Goff (rev.), V-67. Hain-Copinger 15822. ISTC (RLIN), iv00067000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Variant to Hain-Copinger 15822, which does not have the final (blank) leaf. Rubrication: untouched. Binding: stiff vellum, covered with ms. musical notations and Latin words, rubricated in red and blue.
- Brunschwig, Hieronymus, ca. 1450-ca. 1512. Liber de arte distillandi de simplicibus = Das Buch der rechten Kunst zu distilieren die entzige[n] Ding / von Hieronymo Brunschwygk ...[Strasbourg]: Getruckt durch den wol geachte[n] Iohannem Greninger zu[m] Strassburg, in dem achte[n] Tag des Meyen als Man zalt von der Geburt Christi fnfftzehenhundert [8 May 1500], Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1500 .B79 F; [18], CCIX, [3] leaves: ill. (woodcuts); 32 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., v.I, p. 114 (IB.1495). GW 5595. Goff (rev.), B-1227. Hain-Copinger 4021. ISTC (RLIN), ib01227000.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Imperfect: t.p. wanting; title supplied from BM 15th cent., v.I, p. 114 (IB.1495). Binding: blind-stamped decorative brown leather over wooden boards; remains of clasps; paper guards with extensive ms. in Latin, rubricated. In case, with title: Kleines Distillierbuch. Provenance: John Maxson Stillman (bequest bookplate); ms. marginalia.
- Catherine, of Siena, Saint, 1347-1380. Epistole deuotissime / de sancta Catharina da Siena.[Venice]: Stampato in la inclita cita de Venetia in casa de Aldo Manutio Romano, a di xv. [i.e. xix?] septembrio [19 Sept.] 1500., Call No. Spec Coll Rare Books KA1500 .C3 F; [10], ccccxiiii [i.e. 411], [1] leaves: 1 port.; 31 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., V, p. 562 (IB.24504). GW 6222. Goff (rev.) C-281. Hain-Copinger 4688. ISTC, ic00281000. Renouard, p. 23.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Binding: gilt calf, rebacked; red edges. Binder's title: S. Catarina da Siena Epistole. Ald. 1500. Provenance: F.F. Praed. de Woodchester (bookplate); Dominicans of Hinckley, Leicestershire (inscription); royal bookplate with lion unicorn and mottos: Honi soit qui mal y pense; Si Deus pro nobis quis contra nos.
- Eusebius, of Caesarea, Bishop of Caesarea, ca. 260-ca. 340. Ecclesiastica historia diui Eusebii. Et Ecclesiastica historia gentis Anglorum Venerabilis Bede: cu[m]vtraru[m]q[ue] historiaru[m] per singulos libros recollecta capitulorum annotatione. Imp[re]ssi i[n] inclyta ciuitate Argentinen[se] ...: [Georg Husner], anno salutis n[ost]re [1500] xiiij. die Marcij., Call No. Special Collections Rare Books KA1500 .E94; [320] p. (p. [320] blank); 29 cm.
  References: BM 15th cent., I, p. 162 (IB.2377).Goff (rev.) E-129.GW 9439.Hain-Copinger 6714*.ISTC (CD-ROM, 1997 ed.), ie00129000.Proctor 747.Walsh, J.E. 15th cent. printed books, 304.
  Stanford copy: Stanford copy 1 (RBC): Provenance: ms. underscoring and annotations. Bound (2nd) with: Jacobus, de Voragine. Lombardica historia que a plerisq[ue] Aurea legenda sanctoru[m] appellatur. Impresse Argentine: [Georg Husner?], anno Domini M.CCCCC. secu[n]do [1502] ...